警察
Police.
拿身份证出来
Show me your ID.
检查一下　　收到
- Check his ID.    - Yes sir.
袋子里装什么？　　总机
- What's in your bag?    - Headquarter,
打开来看看　　身份证号码C532743
- Let me see.    - please verify ID number C532743…
尾数一，季正雄
Bracket 1, Kwai Ching-hung.
打开
Open it.
协议中有关香港的安排
The arrangement for Hong Kong
不是权宜之计
contained in the agreement are not measures of expediency.
这些安排是长期的政策
它们将写入为香港制定的基本法
They are long-term policies which will be incorporated
五十年不变
in the Basic Law for Hong Kong
and preserved intact for 50 years from 1997.
确保《联合声明》
It is the common interest
不受干扰地全面贯彻实施
as well as shared responsibilities of China and Britain
是中英两国的共同利益
to ensure the Joint Declaration is fully implemented with no encumbrances.
也是我们双方共同的责任
今天下午观塘发生械劫案
An armed robbery took place this afternoon in Kwun Tong.
四名持枪械匪徒
4 armed suspects robbed 5 gold shops on Mut Wah Street.
连环打劫物华街五间金行
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
由观众提供片段，见到贼人离开的时候
In the footage provided by our audience,
在附近秘密执勤的飞虎队员发生枪战
the robbers exchanged fire
双方开枪过百发
with the Special Duties Unit.
事件中，两名途人及三名军装警员受伤
2 passersby and 3 policemen were injured in the incident.
五间金行合共损失大约一千万
The 5 gold shops lost $10M in total.
警方相信，今次械劫案的主谋
The police believe the mastermind
是「头号通缉犯」叶国欢
is the “Most Wanted” Yip Kwok-foon.
一夫当关，万夫莫敌！
Bro foon, you're unbeatable!
真是威风！欢哥！
但大事不妙了！
But shit has hit the fan!
都说放多些报纸！
I told you to put more newspaper underneath!
你看！到处都是血！
Look, there's blood everywhere!
拿去吧，混蛋！
Take it, jerk!
真是很不妙！
Shit has really hit the fan!
两折，不好意思，最多两折！
I can give you 20% tops. Sorry.
说好四折
We agreed on 40%.
还有道义吗？
Don't you have moral principle?
一千万货你只给两百万？
You're paying $2M for $10M's worth of swag?
以前至少五折！
We used to get 50%!
你们销赃的全赚了！
Now you fences are getting it all!
赚你个屁！
We're getting shit!
今时不同往日
Time has changed.
外面的警察盯得很紧！
The cops are on the prowl!
尤其是你的货，欢哥！
Especially for your swag, Bro Foon!
上次那一批，销了两年，足足两年！
It took us 2 years to fence it last time!
炒股、炒楼、炒栗子更能赚钱！
Stocks, real estate, and even chestnuts are more profitable!
帮个忙
Do me a favor.
四折！
40%.
欢哥开口，怎么着都行！
Bro Foon, you always have your way!
不如你找其他买家？
How about you find another fence?
我都买不下手，我看没人敢收⋯
If I can't take it, I doubt others would dare to!
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
开保险箱！
Open the safe!
你算是抢我？
Are you robbing me?
不要逼我自己动手
Don't make me do it.
真的多谢了，欢哥！
Thanks so much, Bro Foon.
以后别来找我
Don't look me up in the future.
不要再合作
There's no more business between us!
各走各路！
We go separate ways!
欢哥，火！
Light, Bro Foon.
船家！
Fisherman!
没事没事
Don't worry.
是「易发」的船
These ships belong to Yi Fa.
什么「易发」？
What's Yi Fa?
番禺「易发」
Yi Fa from Panyu, Guangzhou.
走私电器的！
They smuggle electric appliances.
这么大模大样？如此明目张胆？
So pompously? So brazenly?
人家有靠山，拿牌照做生意的！
They have strong backing. It's legit!
一部电视机，香港卖两千，大陆卖八千
A TV set sells for $2K in Hong Kong and $8K in China.
一趟都数百万！
They earn millions of dollars in each transaction.
赚到笑！
Cash keeps rolling in!
要旧钞，不连号！
Used notes with no consecutive serial numbers.
今天要！
I need them today!
你那边有八千万
You have $80M over there.
五时之前要，你一定要给我！
I want it by 5pm!
你立刻去金库取，马上要！
You go get it. I want it now!
沈经理，筹到多少？
Manager Shum, how much do we have?
霍经理！
Manager Fok!
恋一生　差一些　不可一起
We are in love but can't be together.
只一心　等一天　日月如飞　却等不到你
I wait day by day but you never come back…
愿忘记　又想起你
I want to forget you but you haunt my memory.
卓先生
Mr Cheuk,
要不我们先谈谈银码？
let's discuss the price.
是不是低了点儿？
Was it a bit flat?
不行！再来！
No way! Let's start over!
红笑脸
Red face,
红裙　红丝巾
red skirt, red scarf,
白纸般
like white paper…
我说再唱一次，你听不见？
I said let's start over. Didn't you hear me?
我说再唱一次，你听到没有？
别再浪费时间！
Let's not waste time!
大富翁
Mr Tycoon,
不是说好了三十亿吗？
we agreed on $3 billion.
还谈什么？
That's final.
突然要那么多现金，不可能
It's impossible to get so much cash out of the blue.
我现在手上就这五亿
I've only got $500M on hand.
我有让你走开吗？
Did I say you could go?
五亿，先拿着吧
Take the $500M now.
见好就收
Don't get too greedy.
那我先还一半儿子给你
Then I'll give you back half of your son.
你要上半，还是下半？
You want the upper or lower half?
你真的以为我不敢报警？
Do you really think I won't call the police?
警察知道你儿子在哪儿吗？
Do the cops know where your son is?
最多抓我回去打
All they can do is arrest and torture me.
倒吊、灌水、烧阴囊，全都玩过
四十八小时就会放了我
But after 48 hours, they have to release me.
不过，那时候你儿子就⋯
By that time, however, your son will be…
打电话给警务处处长！
Call the Commissioner of Police!
我刚才说再唱一次，你听不见？
I said let's start over. Didn't you hear me?
那你是这样听得见？还是这样听不见？
You hear me, or not?
耳朵生来不是用来听的吗？
If you can't hear me with your ear,
要是这样都听不见，不如切掉它，好吗？
I might as well cut it off, OK?
不要！不要！
Please don't!
对不起，对不起！
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
早点说，不就没事了吗？
You should've said so earlier.
怎么了？
What's up?
警务处处长不接你电话？
The Commissioner didn't answer?
你耍我的吧？
You're playing me, right?
我就有多大玩多大！
Let's play it all the way then!
胡警官，走这么快？
Leaving so soon, Officer Wu?
大富翁找你！
Mr Tycoon is looking for you.
大富翁！你不是找警察吗？过来！
Mr Tycoon, didn't you call the cops? Come here!
何先生
Mr Ho.
这群狗仔队负责跟我
They are sending these dogs after me,
非常无能
but they are useless.
不然怎会那么容易抓到你儿子？
No wonder it was easy to kidnap your son.
你肯招认了？
So, you are willing to confess?
警察先生！
Officer,
我说干了你娘就真的干了你娘吗？
if I said I'd fucked your mother, did I really fuck her?
人家的儿子在哪儿，你应问当事人
Shouldn't you ask Mr Ho where his son is?
我儿子⋯
My son…
没事
is all right.
我今天来是找大富翁借钱
I came here to borrow money from Mr Tycoon.
不犯法吧？
Is that a crime?
何先生，如果有人威胁你，你说一句
Mr Ho, tell us if he's threatening you.
马上开档案抓人！
We can arrest him right away!
没有
No, he's not.
听见吗？警察先生？
Have you heard it loud and clear, Officer?
我说没有就没有！
I said he's not threatening me!
克制点，皇家警察！
Calm down, Royal Hong Kong Police!
大富翁！
Mr Tycoon,
你刚才说借多少钱给我？
how much will you “lend” me?
三十亿
$3 billion.
David Michael Wu
来广州做生意还是旅？
Are you in Guangzhou for business or leisure?
什么？
Excuse me?
公干？旅游？
Business? Travel?
是，我是商人
Yeah, I am a businessman.
广州站
Guangzhou Railway Station
我要订一个房间
I'd like to reserve a private room
明天八时
at 8pm tomorrow.
姓陈的，谢谢
My name is Chen. Thank you.
连长
Hello, Commander.
明晚八时，风满楼
8pm tomorrow at Fengman Restaurant.
我他妈的是谁？潮哥！
Who the fuck am I? I'm Chiu.
别他妈要我等你！
Don't make me fucking wait for you.
就这样
That's it.
风满楼
Fengman Restaurant
快到了，方老板
Almost there, Mr Fong.
好
OK.
哪间房？
Which room?
好，马上到
OK. Coming.
拿着　　什么？
- Take it.    - What?
拿着，我要戴狗带
Take it. Let me put the tie on.
大宝，这里
Da-bao. This way.
方老板
Mr Fong.
花瓶呢？
Where's the vase?
只是平价货
It's just a cheap one.
行了，走吧
Never mind. Let's go.
陈科
Chief Chen.
我来介绍
This is Zhang Da-bao, Boss Zhang,
这位就是接手「易发」铺位的张大宝
张总！
who has bought Yi Fa.
这位就是工商局陈科
This is Chief Chen from Industry and Commerce.
好兄弟来的！
We're buddies.
陈科你好
Nice to meet you, Chief Chen.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
喝一杯
Let's have a drink.
大家先喝一杯
Let's drink together.
来，坐
Have a seat.
干杯
Bottoms up!
张总不会喝吗？
Boss Zhang cannot drink?
干呀！
Bottoms up!
我说干杯！
I said bottoms up!
是
Yes!
干，干
Bottoms up!
大宝是好兄弟
Da-bao is my buddy.
我们认识不久
We've only met quite recently.
但是一见如故，相逢恨晚！
But we hit it off right away!
陈科
Chief Chen,
帮帮他吧
please help him.
咦？这个花瓶是贵价货！
This vase must be expensive!
小小意思
Just a modest gift.
老规矩
Here's how it works:
陈科玩腻了，就让回给张总！
when Chief Chen grows tired of it, Boss Zhang can buy it back!
那至少值三十万！
It's worth at least RMB¥300K!
不是说好了二十万吗？
Didn't we agree on RMB¥200K?
我看错？
I got the price wrong?
老猫烧须？
Oh, even Homer sometimes nods.
怎会？
No way!
说到古董，陈科才是专家
Chief Chen is a connoisseur.
我们哪会懂，对吧？
What do we know?
陈科说三十便三十
If Chief Chen says RMB¥300K, then it's RMB¥300K.
明天上来工商局拿批文
Come get the business license tomorrow.
我找个漂亮的框镶好给你
I'll have it nicely framed for you.
谢谢陈科
Thanks so much, Chief Chen.
好兄弟
We're buddies.
张总，看看想吃什么？
Boss Zhang, what would you like to eat?
咸菜扣肉
Braised pork with preserved vegetables.
我才不吃肥腻的
That's too oily for me.
让我来点菜
Let me order.
就吃鱼虾蟹海鲜餐，好吗？
Shall we have a seafood platter?
我去叫
Let me order it.
服务员！
Waiter!
张总，祝你生意兴隆
Mr Zhang, best of luck with your business!
好，多谢
Thanks a lot.
喝一杯
Cheers.
干
Bottoms up!
干！
这一个，逢星期日，打高球，清水湾
This guy plays golf every Sunday in Clear Water Bay.
单行路，够清静，电话有盲点，可以考虑
One-way road. Quiet. No phone signal. It may work.
饭还没到吗？
Hey! Where's our rice?
下一个
Next.
这个好办
This one is easy.
超级玩家
A super playboy.
每晚喝到天昏地暗
Drunk every night.
最近还包养了小明星
He recently has an actress as a mistress.
喂
Hey!
饭呢？
Where is our rice?
饭，稍等我一下
Rice? Give me a second.
饭马上来，很快
Your rice is coming right away.
有时候，司机会被支开
Sometimes he would send his driver away.
不好意思，让你们久等
Sorry to keep you waiting.
请慢用
Enjoy your food.
关门
Close the door.
先生，这边请
Sir, please follow me.
给我一杯茶
Give me a cup of tea.
喂！你刚不是去厕所吗？
Hey! Haven't you gone to the bathroom just now?
不要吐　　饭是冷的！
- Wait! Don't puke.    - Hey! The rice is cold!
你稍等我一下
Give me a second.
不好意思，饭是冷的吗？　　我要茶！
- I'm sorry. The rice is cold?    - I want tea.
快点　　小姐，麻烦你告诉我⋯
- Hurry up!    - Tell me the room number…
我要茶！　　等我一下，我带你去
- I want tea.    - Give me a second. I'll show you the way.
茶，我帮你拿
Sure, I'll get you tea.
等一下，你们都等我一下，马上回来
Give me a second. I will be right back.
将就一下吧
Take it easy.
上来聊才能甩掉那些狗仔队
We came to China to shake off those cop dogs.
你上次玩得那么大！
You went too far last time!
要玩就玩大的
I live life to the full.
人生就这样
C'est la vie.
不然怎么精彩？
There's no other way.
我们之前偷车、爆窃、打劫运钞车
We've stolen cars, committed burglaries,
一次比一次厉害！
and robbed cash vans.
连大富翁都动了
We even kidnapped the tycoon's son.
还绑架？
Should we do more kidnappings?
那你想到什么好主意？
What do you have in mind?
说出来，我们商量一下
Spit it out. We can discuss.
我是一个攀山运动员
I'm a mountaineer.
我征服了一座山
After conquering one mountain,
当然得再找一座更高、更难爬的山
I need to find a higher and harder mountain.
就这样
That's it.
还没找到那座山
Before finding that mountain,
先找钱吧
let's find the money first.
继续
Let's keep doing it.
郑建权，五十三岁
Cheng, 53 years old.
没儿没女，老婆当家
No children. His wife is in charge.
以前一万多块钱一部，谁买得起？
A mobile phone used to cost over RMB¥10K. Who could afford that?
你以为谁都是高干子弟？
Not everyone is a child of a high-ranking official.
现在愈便宜愈好
Now the cheaper, the better.
我们一千万人口
We have a population of 10 million.
你算算
Say RMB¥1K a set,
对，一千块钱一部
RMB¥10K for 10 sets.
十部就一万块，那时候就发过周润发了
We will be fatter than Chow Yun-fat!
对，现在没人用传呼机了
Beepers are already outdated.
好了，不说了，谈正事，一会儿再聊
OK, I'll talk to you later.
潮哥，不好意思
Excuse me, Boss.
继续讲吧
Please go on.
你别难为小的了，小生意
Don't give us a hard time. We're doing small business.
不说我的事了，潮哥，这帮小弟很棒
Big Bro, these kids are great.
走最前的老鬼在香港有案底
The guy who came in first has criminal record in Hong Kong.
你带来有个屁用
Don't know why you brought him here.
混蛋，叫你带些像样的来
I told you to bring some decent-looking guys.
全都贼眉贼眼，都是蠢货
They all look like criminals and idiots.
干你娘的，你该收山了
You should be out of business.
他看什么？
What is he staring at?
可是这个很聪明、很能干的
He is smart and helpful
蓝衣那个也不要
I don't want the guy in blue either.
这次两个就够了？
You only need two men this time?
带他们去开开眼界嘛
Take the others to broaden their horizons.
明白，完全明白
Got it!
我去安排
Let me see to it.
你看看看，他妈的看什么？
What are you fucking looking at?
走了，向阳、老胡
You, you, get lost!
走了！别喝了！走了！
Stop drinking and scram!
你们两个，跟我进来
You two come with me.
快点了，快点了
Faster.
慢死了
So slow!
潮哥
Big Bro Chiu,
王磊
Wang Lei.
红旗
Hong Qi.
叫潮哥
Say Big Bro Chiu.
潮哥！
Big Bro Chiu!
听得懂广东话吧？
They understand Cantonese?
懂，当然懂
Of course!
来！先喝一杯
Come have a drink.
装扮一下来香港见我
Spruce them up before sending them to Hong Kong.
好，一定，我会的
Sure will!
他妈的
Motherfucker.
坐，吃饭
Sit and eat.
连长
Commander,
这潮哥是什么来头？
who's this Big Bro Chiu?
他就是不让你知道他什么来头
Who cares if he is Big Bro Chiu or not?
他这个贱人
He is a douchebag.
反正就是见一个人
He is a sly,
就换一个名字的老狐狸
old fox who changes identities.
跟他妈早年香港那个隐形贼王季正雄
He looks fucking like Kwai Ching-hung,
一个他妈的样子
the invisible King of Thieves in Hong Kong.
那个季正雄杀掉警察被通缉
Kwai Ching-hung disappeared
就销声匿迹了
after killing cops.
然后又蹦出个潮哥出来
Then Big Bro Chiu popped up.
「潮哥」，不就是个名字而已
Big Bro Chiu is just a name.
大辉在吗？
Is Fai here?
阿辉
Fai.
什么事？
What's up?
有人找你　　喂
- Someone is looking for you.    - Hey.
可乐哥
Bro Coke?
喂
Hey!
泰国人？
She's Thai?
Noon，去买可乐
Noon, go buy a dozen of Cokes.
你什么时候回来的？
When did you come back?
刚刚回来
Just now.
你干什么？这么客气，进来坐
You are too kind. Come in and have a seat.
你说泰语吗？
Did you just speak Thai?
难道我讲法语吗？
Do you think I speak French?
好臭！
You stink!
是吗？
Really?
宝儿
Bo.
你怎能这么没规矩？
How can you be so rude?
进去帮爸爸开饭
Come help set the table.
你坐一下，很快开饭
Dinner will be served soon.
你真顽皮
Naughty girl.
去洗手
Go wash your hands.
刚才洗过了
I did wash my hands.
你昨天吃过饭，今天要不要吃？就是嘛
You ate yesterday. Are you going to eat today?
慢慢来，宝儿，这么着急
Bo, slow down. Don't rush.
可乐哥
Bro Coke.
想喝吗？
You want some?
我跟你一人一半吧
Shall we share it?
别让她喝
Don't let her drink it.
早前又咳嗽了，不然又要花钱看医生
She was coughing. I don't wanna spend money on meds.
我没咳嗽，只是发烧而已
I wasn't coughing. I just had a fever.
对，只是喝一点
It's all right to have a sip.
什么没咳嗽？你就会顶嘴！
Not coughing? You are being cheeky!
总之不能喝
I say no Coke.
辉，我不吃，快要迟到
Fai, I'm not gonna eat. I'm running late.
现在就出去？
You're going now?
是的
Yes.
乖乖的
Be a good girl.
可乐哥，吃饭
Bro Coke, dig in.
她不吃？
She's not eating with us?
她去上夜班
She has to work night shift.
她做按摩师的
She's a legit masseuse.
吃块烧肉
Eat some barbecued pork.
来，吃蔬菜
Bo, eat some veggies.
经常不吃蔬菜
You seldom eat veggies.
去不去海洋公园？
Shall we go to Ocean Park?
玩过云霄飞车吗？想玩吗？
Shall we ride the roller coaster?
我带你飞高一点，远一点，好吗？
Shall we fly higher and farther?
不答我？搔你痒
Tickle, tickle.
不要那么吵，要不然房东太太又骂人了
Stop making noise, or the landlady will be nasty.
她骂你没交房租吧
She's nasty because you haven't paid the rent.
还顶嘴，下来
You're being cheeky. Come down.
厉害，臭丫头，敢跟老爸顶嘴
What a dragon lady, arguing with your father!
这丫头，一玩就忘形了！穿好拖鞋
This girl plays too much! Wear your slippers.
做好功课没有？快点，进去做功课
Have you finished your homework? Homework first.
快点！
Quick!
我待会打你屁股　　真乖
- I'll spank you.    - Good girl.
这丫头！
This naughty girl!
戒了
I've quit smoking.
戒了？
Quit?
戒了
I've quit smoking.
「嫖赌饮荡吹⋯
"Whoring, gambling, drinking, roaming…
戒了不够帅」
and smoking are the hobbies of a king."
是你说的
Your mantra.
我要洗肾，不戒不行
I'm on dialysis. I have to quit.
早就说你肾亏
Told you you're impotent.
一蹲下就头晕
You feel dizzy when you squat.
去！
Fuck!
最近在干什么？
What have you been up to?
我可以干什么？
What can I do?
以前干地盘临时工
I used to do temporary construction work.
现在全职带女儿
Now I'm a full-time babysitter.
你呢？
What about you?
我？
Me?
我卖这个去大陆
I sell this in China.
以后没有人用传呼机了
People won't use beepers anymore.
将来大陆人一人一部
Every Chinese will own a mobile phone in the future.
一部卖一千，十部一万
One sells for RMB¥1K, 10 for RMB¥10K.
发过周润发
I'll be fatter than Chow Yun-fat.
那么发？
Fat with loads of money?
真厉害
Great.
你真好，做老板了
You're doing great. You're becoming a boss.
也对，走正路总比以前走偏门好
Going straight is better than going astray.
我和你都不够狠，做不成大贼
We're not fierce enough to be Kings of Thieves.
尽干些偷鸡摸狗的勾当
All we did were some petty crimes.
生活没保障，觉也睡不好
Our life was insecure. We couldn't sleep well.
又不是赚很多，也不知为了什么
And we didn't earn that much. So what's the point?
我想在这里住几天
I'd like to stay here for a few days.
什么？
What?
我睡沙发就可以
I can sleep on the couch.
干什么？
What's that for?
收下吧，帮补一下阿嫂
Take it. It will lessen your wife's burden.
爸爸，手册不见了！
Dad, I can't find my school manual!
爸爸，爸爸
Dad, Dad.
来了！
Coming!
行了
That's fine
(Gold shop)
(Jockey Club)
番禺易发市场
Panyu Yi Fa Market
三十部廿九吋新画皇，每部一万二
30 sets of 29-inch TVs. RMB¥12K apiece.
另外八十部VCD机，每部四千
Plus 80 VCD players. RMB¥4K apiece.
多谢你，六十八万
RMB¥680K, thank you.
收了你七十万
You pay me RMB¥700K.
货到通知你
I will notify you once the goods are delivered.
下一个
Next.
陈科的三十万，你点算一下
RMB¥30K for Chief Chen. Please count it.
企业法人营业执照
Business License
三十万，数目正确
RMB¥30K. The amount is correct.
货到第一时间通知你
Will notify you once the goods are on board.
替我多谢陈科
Please extend my thanks to Chief Chen.
我家的VCD机坏了
My VCD player is broken.
送你一部新的，金
I'll give you a new one. Kam.
是
Yes.
新款的三十三吋新画皇
The latest 33-inch TV set.
好东西
Good stuff.
也送给你吧
I'll give it to you, too.
多谢张总
Thanks so much, Boss Zhang.
不用客气
You're welcome.
阿贵、阿广，拿部三十三吋新画皇
Gui, Guang, a 33-inch TV set and a VCD player.
还有一部VCD机
好
Sure.
大宝电器
Da-bao Electronics
贪得无厌
She is greedy.
做生意便是这样了
That's business.
别整天摆副臭脸
Don't pull a long face all day long.
张总！张总！
Boss Zhang, Boss Zhang.
放心，他们俩会搞定
No worries. They will take care of it.
快点　　什么事？
- Quick    - What's wrong?
张总
Boss Zhang.
什么事？
What's wrong?
货物出事了？
Something wrong with the goods?
不是，关门
No, close the door.
关门
Close the door.
嘴这么硬？打给你老婆报平安
Want to play tough guy? Call your wife now.
打给你老婆
Call your wife now.
报平安，混蛋
Tell your folks you're OK, asshole.
打死我，你一分钱也拿不到
If you kill me, you won't get a cent.
敢唬弄我？
Are you threatening me?
卓，耐心点
Cheuk, be patient.
他再不说，就断他粮水吧
If he doesn't talk, don't give him food or water.
你好吵
You're so noisy.
喂，干什么？
Hey, what are you doing?
捡他上来，捡上来！
Get him back! Get him back!
这里是金宝珠宝金行
This is the gold shop.
平常会有一辆警车在门口
Usually there's a police wagon at the entrance.
对面街有马会
Jockey Club is across the street.
我们在里面看紧
We keep a close eye on the police wagon.
待八时警车离去，我们立刻动手
As soon as it leaves at 8pm, we rob the gold shop right away.
那天跑夜马，会有好多人，搞定之后⋯
It's the racing night. It will be crowded. After it's done…
赚不了钱！　　记得要跟紧我
- There's not much money in this.    - Follow me closely.
你刚说什么？
What did you just say?
你们做大茶饭的
You've committed big crimes.
怎么就打劫小金行？
Why pick this small gold shop?
对啊
Yes,
听人家说，你们三大贼王合作
I've heard the 3 Kings of Thieves would join forces.
没几个亿，都有几千万了
At least millions of dollars will be involved.
什么三大贼王？
What 3 Kings of Thieves?
说吧！
Say it!
欢哥，你是否真的重出江湖
Bro Foon, are you making a comeback?
跟卓子强、季正雄
This time with Cheuk Tze-keung and Kwai Ching-hung.
三大贼王合作做大案？
The 3 Kings of Thieves are collaborating?
有人看到你们三人在大陆见面
Someone has seen you three meeting in China.
你从哪儿听回来的？
Where did you hear this?
外面全这么说
Everyone is saying that.
这你也信！
And you believe it?
老大不是说过，拿枪混不到饭吃！
Didn't Big Bro say you couldn't make money by toting guns?
如果我是季正雄
If I'm Kwai,
就不用和你们一起吃盒饭
I don't have to eat lunch boxes with you.
蠢货
Idiots.
神经病
That's ridiculous!
一个「砰！砰！砰！」
Yip is all noise and fury.
一个鬼鬼祟祟
Kwai is hush and shush.
三个风格不一样，搞什么？
We are so different. How can it work?
跟我走私多些电器
Smuggle more goods with me.
一起赚到笑！
Let's make more money together!
收到
Got it.
英明！
Brilliant!
有时心痒，也想重拾枪杆
Sometimes I feel like toting my gun again.
打劫！打劫！
Robbery! Robbery!
多威风！
That's so cool!
你这叫威风？
You call that cool?
老大开AK才威风！
Big Bro wielding AK-47 is cool!
不是这样开
Not like this.
AK后座力大
AK-47 recoil is powerful.
不是托着
Don't hold it.
而是按着
Press it.
站稳马步
Stand firm.
射他老子
Shoot the hell out of him.
怎么了？跟就跟
What the fuck?! Join me
不跟就回去吃屎
or go home and eat shit.
潮哥，那⋯
Big Bro Chiu,
我们打个小金行，能赚多少钱？
how much can we earn from robbing this gold shop?
打不打电话？
You're calling or not?
你们觉得，如果三大贼王合作
If the 3 Kings of Thieves join forces,
就算开「鱼蛋档」
even if we open a fish ball stall together,
也很轰动吧？
we will create a stir, right?
起什么名字好呢？
What shall I call our stall?
打不打电话？
Are you calling your family or not?
不要睡！
Hey, wake up!
金库？
Gold depository?
马场？
Racecourse?
绑架彭定康？
Kidnap Hong Kong Governor Chris Patten?
鲁平？
The Head of Hong Kong and Macau Affairs, Lu Ping?
不行
No way.
搞什么？
What are you listening to?
四大天王同台演出
The 4 Heavenly Kings singing on stage together.
唱什么歌？
What are they singing?
唱什么也听不到，有什么好听？
I can't hear a thing. What's so good about it?
四大天王破天荒第一次合唱
When the 4 Heavenly Kings sing together,
唱什么也很厉害
it's terrific no matter what they sing.
我要水，水！
Water, give me water.
我肯打了，我打了
I will make the call.
我丈夫怎么样？我求求你！
How's my husband? I beg you!
他身体不好，别为难他
He's not in good health. Don't hurt him.
你别以为我们很有钱，只是表面风光
We are not as loaded as it may seem.
卓先生，你怎么才肯放过我丈夫？
Mr Cheuk, can you let my husband go?
要不你开个价，我自己掏腰包⋯
Name a price. I'll pay you from my own pocket…
喂？
Hello?
要不这样，我有八千万现金
I have $80M in cash.
全给你好吗？
Is it OK?
就八千吧
$80M it is!
给我找叶国欢、季正雄！
Find Yip and Kwai!
搞什么？
What the hell?
三大贼王破天荒第一次合作
The 3 Kings of Thieves join forces for the first time.
搞什么都厉害！
It will be terrific no matter what we do!
什么也没想到
You don't even have a plan yet,
找两个通缉犯放在身边
and you want 2 wanted men around you?
我一定能想到
You know I will
你知道我一定能想得到的！
come up with a plan!
这座山，就是我要找的山
This is the mountain I'm looking for.
喜玛拉雅山！
Himalaya!
吃宵夜？
Having night snack?
冰箱有可乐
There's Coke in the fridge.
行，自己来
OK, I'll get it myself.
辉，你朋友要住到什么时候？
Fai, how long is your friend staying?
三、四晚吧
3 or 4 nights.
我们有个女儿
We have a daughter.
突然家中多了个男人
I don't feel comfortable…
不是很方便
with a guy suddenly staying with us.
他做什么工作的？
What does he do?
卖手提电话的
He sells mobile phones.
别说了
Don't worry.
睡吧
Go to sleep.
好的
OK.
我缝好衣服就去睡觉
I'll go to bed after sewing.
正在带客人过来，三分钟到
I will arrive with clients in 3 minutes.
收到
Got it.
阿贵、阿广，卸货，赶快！
Gui, Guang, unload the goods. Be quick.
老大，出事了！
Big Bro, we have a situation!
番禺海关
Panyu Customs!
金，金！
Kam! Kam!
阿忠，停车
Chung, pull over!
你去那边看看
Take a look over there.
你再到那边看一下
Take a look again over there.
别动，手放头上
Don't move. Hands on your head.
走
Let's go.
走啊！
那阿金怎么办？
What about Kam?
找方老板
Find Mr Fong.
中国海关
Chinese customs
同志
Comrade.
什么事？
What do you want?
我们来找龙科长
We're looking for Chief Long.
想请教一下
We're wondering
莲花山那批货还有人，能不能通融通融？
if he can discharge the Lianhuashan goods and men?
我们认识方老板的
We know Mr Fong.
四日立案，上报省厅
In 4 days, the goods will be confiscated
货物充公，人就枪毙
and the men will be executed.
是，明白明白
Yes, we understand.
科长，有人找你
Chief, someone wants to see you.
好，好⋯
OK.
龙科今天很忙
Chief Long is busy today.
明天再来吧
Come again tomorrow.
好，是⋯
All right. Yes…
龙科今天不见客
Chief Long is not seeing guests today.
明天再来吧
Come again tomorrow.
混蛋
Asshole.
在这耍大牌！
Who do you think you are?
是否不想救阿金？
You don't want to save Kam anymore?
好，是⋯
Yes, yes.
龙科说，晚上再谈
Chief Long said he wanted to talk over dinner.
你先找个馆子等他
Find a restaurant and wait for him.
好
Good.
风满楼，风满楼！
Fengman Restaurant.
喂
Hello?
我跟龙科在大富贵啊
I am in Fugui Restaurant with Chief Long.
好，马上来
Coming right away.
走
Let's go.
记得拿花瓶
Remember to bring a vase.
拿花瓶
Take the vase.
快些！
Quick!
行⋯
Okay!
快点！
Hurry up!
海关龙科
Chief Long of Customs.
我好兄弟来的
He's my buddy.
龙科你好
Chief Long, nice to meet you.
有人架子真大，官等人！
I'm an official but you made me wait!
不好意思
Sorry,
我去了风满楼
I went to Fengman Restaurant.
风满楼的东西能吃吗？
Is the food there edible?
就是，他不懂吃！
He knows nothing about food!
饮食之道，龙科才是专家
Chief Long is a foodie.
是⋯
Yes, you're right.
龙科，他是我的好兄弟
Chief Long, he's my buddy.
这一次，帮帮他吧
Help him this time.
麻烦你
Thank you.
你兄弟，不是我兄弟
He's your buddy, not mine.
我不是每个都帮，只帮朋友！
I only help my friends!
谈得合，玩得开，便是朋友
If we hit it off, we're friends.
饿了！
I'm hungry!
先叫菜吧
Let's order first.
是，应该点菜了
Yes, let's order.
吃什么？吃什么？
What would you like?
吃什么？
咸菜扣肉
Braised pork with preserved vegetables.
这么粗，你吃吧！
It's not refined enough for me.
鲍参翅肚！
Let's order delicacies.
服务员！
Waiter!
多谢
Thanks a lot.
你，叫什么总？
What's your name?
张总
Boss Zhang.
张总是吧？
Boss Zhang, right?
你这个人，有意思！有意思！
You're a fun guy! A fun guy!
谢谢
Thank you.
龙科，那事就拜托你
Chief Long, thanks for your help.
我们去找间 KTV，先唱歌吧
Let's sing karaoke first.
好，KTV
OK, karaoke first.
阿忠
Chung
KTV 的卡片，还有电话
Give me name cards of karaoke bars and the phone.
下一场了
Let's go for more fun.
不行了⋯
I can't…
先泡个澡
Let's take a bath.
泡澡，泡澡好
It's good to take a bath.
找间桑拿
Find a sauna.
不要忘了花瓶啊
Don't forget the vase.
是⋯
Yes.
中国海关
Chinese customs
幸好有关系，不用蹲监仓
Thanks to connections, I didn't need to rot in jail.
住宾馆
We stayed in a motel,
有床有电视，伙食也不差
with a bed, TV, OK food,
只是不能召妓！
though no whores!
你们说，是不是很好？
It's not bad, huh? What do you say?
对⋯
Yes, yes.
混蛋，又不是你招呼那些官！
Asshole, you didn't need to carouse with those officials!
吃吃喝喝也埋怨？
Don't complain about carousing,
看在钱的份上
for money's sake.
喂，你们过来
Hey! Come here.
我们的货！
Our goods!
来⋯
Come.
看看你们的货，都在这里了
Your goods are here.
看一看，有没有问题？
Take a look. Any problems?
感谢⋯
Thanks so much.
等我看一下对不对
Let me take a look.
没问题的话，在这里签个字，别弄错了
Sign here if there's no problem.
感谢
Thanks so much.
行了
OK.
叫你派线人到警察局找季正雄的档案
Your mole hasn't found Kwai's dossier
还没找到？
in the police station?
那么叶国欢潜逃回大陆，还没找到？
No news about Yip in China?
以前跟他混的那些手下、销赃那些呢？
What about his underlings? His fences?
一块儿偷渡来的？同乡呢？
His fellow illegal immigrants? His village mates?
也找不到？
Can't find them?
没有？
Nothing at all?
好
Good.
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
警察悬红一百多万
The cops have offered a $1M reward on him.
这么多年都没消息
But there's no news over these years.
你再给我一点时间
Give me some time.
悬红可以考虑
Reward money is a good idea.
警察出一百多万，我就出一千万！
The cops offer $1M; I'll up it to $10M!
不够？再出一亿！
If it's not enough, then $100M!
我开一条专线
I'll set up a special phone line.
谁报料，谁就有钱收
Whoever knows their whereabouts will get the money.
那么张扬？警察一定窃听
So brazenly? The cops will tap the phone.
你们三个贼王聚在一起
Those assholes will prevent the 3 Kings from meeting up.
那群混蛋一定拦路的
未必
Not necessarily.
警察不知多想找到他们
The cops want them too.
肯定派很多人来打听
They will send loads of people after us.
想想怎么甩掉他们吧
Find a way to shake them off.
喂
Hello?
是卓老板吗？
Are you Cheuk?
是
Yes.
明天十二时，在庙街打把紫色伞
Noon tomorrow. Bring a purple umbrella to Temple Street.
我找人接你
I'll have you picked up.
上车
Get on.
脱衣服
Take off your clothes.
全脱掉
Take them all off.
季正雄，跟他合作过一次，很普通
I worked with Kwai once. He's so average.
叶国欢，我认识他，住在海陆丰那个
I know Yip. He lived in Guangdong.
季正雄本名是邢镇南
Kwai's real name is Xing Zhennan.
我帮他兴建祖屋的
His ancestral house was built by me.
是
Yes.
就这样了
OK.
我当过叶国欢司机，被警察追
I drove for Yip and was chased by the cops.
叶国欢的货，也是我销的
I fenced for Yip.
叶国欢打劫时我也在现场的
I was present in Yip's every heist.
大家都一起开AK
We wielded AK-47s together.
卓老板，我好羡慕你，你所有新闻我都看过
Mr Cheuk, I envy you. I admire all your works.
叶国欢曾光顾过我
Yip bought sex from me.
他那时粗声粗气，很厉害的
He was loud and proud.
打劫？香港仔？
Heists? Hong Kong kids?
打架最在行，鬼祟又没胆
These barking dogs are sneaky wussies.
旗兵，是鼎爷我第一个引入的，知道吗？
I imported the Chinese retired soldiers to Hong Kong.
打劫前，最重要教他们什么？
What did I teach them before a heist?
道义两个字！
Moral principle!
省港旗兵之父
Father of the Chinese retired soldiers,
进入正题没有？
can you cut to the chase?
你究竟认识叶国欢，还是季正雄？
Do you know Yip or Kwai?
别打断老子讲话
Don't interrupt me when I talk.
说得快你又听不懂！
If I talk too fast, you won't understand!
我说到哪里？
Where was I?
道义两个字
Moral principle.
我有一次，带大圈文、湖南鬼、潮州威
I once brought 3 Mainlanders
跟警察驳火的时候，「砰！砰！砰！」
to a showdown with the cops. Bang!
潮州威吓得枪都掉了！
One of them, Wei, was so scared he dropped his gun!
你知道吗？是我冲过去救他的！
You know what? I rushed to save him!
所以他欠我很多，知道吗？
He owes me a lot.
知道昆西是谁吗？
Know who Kun-xi is?
叶国欢以前的老大？
Yip's former boss?
就是潮州威的干儿子
Quincy is Wei's godson.
想见他吗？
Want to meet him?
一百万！
$1M!
要查清楚他
You better check him out thoroughly.
我查你妈的
Check me out? Motherfucker.
一百万而已
It's just $1M.
但是要快
Act fast.
明天站在你俩面前
Quincy will stand in front of you tomorrow.
来⋯
Give me the dough.
喂
Hey.
多谢
Thanks so much!
带你去逛街好吗？
Let's go have some fun?
怎么了，台山仔，最近手头很紧？
Are you tight in cash lately, Taishan Boy?
三根枪够用了吗？
How can 3 pieces be enough?
枪不是用来嗅的，是用来开的
Guns are for firing, not for sniffing.
长官教我们：安全第一
Our commander taught us: safety first.
那你嗅这么久
Have you sniffed out that Cheuk is looking for Yip and Kwai?
有否嗅到卓子强，在找叶国欢和季正雄？
卓老板说，要找那两位大哥聊一聊
Mr Cheuk says he wants to meet those two.
看，他开了专线
Look, he has set up a special phone line.
报料也有奖金
Info for money.
多豪爽！
How generous!
他们二人很危险的
Both of them are very dangerous.
不危险，怎么做大哥？
Which kingpin is not dangerous?
他们搞那么大？
They are being so brazen?
快要回归了
The Handover is imminent.
就是快回归才要干一次大的
Because the Handover is imminent, you have to do big!
回归之后，连饭也不给你吃，蠢货
After the Handover, it will be slim pickings, Idiot.
这样吧
Listen.
你替我打听一下
Sniff out their whereabouts.
我喝茶、吃饭、装修也全靠你了！
The restoration of this Association depends on you!
老弟，有消息就告诉我
Keep me posted, kiddo.
有消息就告诉我
Keep me posted!
先生，请站住
Stand still, sir.
什么事？
What's wrong?
去哪？
Where are you going?
回家
Home.
身份证
Your ID, please.
宝儿！
Bo!
你为何放学不立即回家？
Why didn't you come home right after school?
跟你说过几多次
I told you so many times.
你去了哪里？
Where have you been?
我们四处找你啊！
We've been looking for you everywhere.
可乐哥，接走她也通知一声嘛
Bro Coke, you should've told us beforehand.
我刚好顺路　　吓坏我们了
- I thought I was on my way.    - You've scared the hell out of us.
不要吵！
Shut up!
还喝？还不听话！
Still drinking? Bad girl!
什么事？
What happened?
小女孩顽皮
She's naughty.
教女儿回家教嘛
Teach your girl at home, not on the street.
不好意思　　把小女孩吓坏了
- I'm sorry.    - You've frightened her.
是，不好意思⋯
Yes, I'm sorry.
先回家吧
Let's go home.
感谢
Thank you, sir.
不好意思
Sorry.
傻丫头
Darling.
爸爸疼妳
Daddy loves you.
乖女
My good girl.
三天
3 Days!
只用了三天，货就找回来，人也抓到了
Chief Song helped us recover the goods in 3 days.
宋局，你真是好兄弟
Chief Song, my buddy!
牛！
You rock!
维护社会治安，也是我们公安的天职嘛
It's incumbent on the police to maintain order.
算不了什么
张总
Boss Zhang,
我倒要请你帮个忙
can you do me a favor?
走
Go!
让他消消气
Let him vent his anger.
还跑！
Stop!
品茶之道，宋局才是专家
Chief Song, you're a tea connoisseur.
够了
Enough.
我倒要你帮个忙
I need you to do me a favor.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他们俩，是我当兵时
They are the sons of my ex-commander's friend.
老首长朋友的儿子
这事别追究了
Forgive them.
给我一个面子
Give me face.
他们抢我
They robbed me.
你这次也没什么损失
What have you lost?
他们敢抢我，抢我！
They robbed me! Me!
好兄弟嘛
We're good buddies.
你是谁？
Who do you think you are?
小资！
A petite bourgeois!
一个唯利是图、走私逃税的小资
A greedy, smuggling, tax-evading petite bourgeois!
不要把自己看得这么重
Don't think too highly of yourself.
我们是好兄弟⋯
We're good buddies.
抓走他们！
Take them away!
好兄弟⋯
We're good buddies.
毙了他
Shoot him,
我就依法办事
I'll act according to the law!
幸好⋯
Great, there's a vase in the toilet…
幸好厕所有⋯
We're lucky…
小小的，先顶替
It's small but it will do.
好兄弟
We're good buddies.
老板，多谢二百万
RMB¥2M, thank you!
收你一百三十万，多谢
I receive RMB¥1.3M from you. Thanks.
货到通知你
I'll notify you once we have the goods.
下一位
Next.
慢慢看，慢慢挑
Take your time.
疯了！
It's insane!
出去等，先出去，出去
Everyone out.
出去等，全都出去！
Get out!
疯了，疯了！
It's insane!
你做什么？
What happened?
欢哥，卓子强真的疯了
Bro Foon, Cheuk has gone mad!
他真的开了专线找你！
He set up a special phone line to look for you.
胡警官
Inspector Wu.
你知道你有多难跟吧？
You're difficult to tail.
只能站这儿等你
I had to wait here for you!
帮你抓到这家伙
I caught this guy for you.
他说收了你一百万，帮你找昆西
He said you gave him $1M for Kun-xi's whereabouts.
找人犯法的吗？
Is it a crime to look for someone?
不犯法
No.
但你查清楚他的底细没有？
But have you checked him out?
这家伙刚刚蹲了十多二十年
He's been in jail for 20 years.
他进牢时，香港电话才是六位数！
The phone numbers back then only had 6 digits!
现在脱节了！
He's out of touch now!
脱什么节？
Out of touch?
我上去大陆，潮州威跑出来接我啊！
If I go to China, Wei will pick me up!
潮州威？
Wei?
两年前被枪毙了！
He was shot dead two years ago!
就是被昆西出卖的！
Kun-xi betrayed him!
是不是被骗？
Have you been conned?
我可以立刻逮捕他
I can arrest him now if you have.
江湖救急，有借有还
An eye for an eye.
道义啊⋯
That's moral principle.
克制点！
Calm down!
我已经很克制
I'm very calm.
要不然，我连你也揍了！
Or I'd have kicked you too!
报不报警啊？
Want to report the crime?
你不报警我就放人了
If not, I'll let him go.
怎么样？
Well?
不报警？那我就放人了！
If not, I'll let him go!
叫完就滚吧！
Get lost!
你袭警？　　别耍花样
- Are you assaulting a police officer?    - Don't play tricks.
打你又怎样？吃屎狗！
So what? Motherfucker!
不要气馁
Don't give up,
继续找他们
keep searching for him.
我们皇家警察抓不抓到人就看你！
The Royal Hong Kong Police relies on your phone calls.
靠你的电话啊！
收手吧！
Why don't you just drop it?
无谓聪明一世，蠢钝一时
Don't ruin your impeccable record.
有办法我一定帮你！
I'd help you if I could!
就算打我
Even if you were to hit me,
我也要说，死路一条！
I must say it's a dead end!
我知道，我知道了！
I know, I know!
来到今晚最重要的场合
We've come to the climax of tonight.
就是3T的尾关
The last leg of the Triple Trio.
这场关系到一亿七千万的多宝彩池
The $170M jackpot pool.
加上投注总额，相信一注独中
Plus the total bet amount. A single winner
会有超过三亿派彩，事关重大
can collect over $300M.
现在有很多马迷集中投注
Many horse racing fans are placing bets.
全城哄动！
The whole city is abuzz!
一注独中的话，真是「肥过肥猪仔」
A single winning ticket will make you richer than any king.
那就看有没有人能拿到了
See if you can win.
投注都集中在大热门「追风神驹」身上
Bets are placed on Wind Chaser.
冷门马有很多
Gold Weather is the horse least expected to win.
最冷的是「好天气」，是九十九倍
The odds are 99.
全买独赢及位置
Win & Place.
他妈的，彩池升到三、四亿了！
Motherfucker, almost $400M in the pool.
一场3T就抢光香港人的钱了
Hong Kong citizens are robbed by the Triple Trio.
3T什么意思？
What does Triple Trio mean?
这场赛事的一亿七千多万的多宝奖金
The $170M jackpot pool
吸引到很多人下注
has attracted many fans queuing to place their bets.
没夹子了？
No more clothes pegs?
没了
No.
帮我去拿
Go get some in the room.
是
Sure.
好，随时开跑了！
The race is about to start.
一亿七千万的多宝彩池
The $170M jackpot pool.
如果一注独中的话
A single winner
就有超过三亿的派彩了！
can collect over $300M!
就看看哪位幸运儿能一注独中
Who will be the lucky one?
如果爆冷门的话
A dark horse will increase the size
彩池累积奖金就会更多了
of the betting pool.
马匹全部入闸，都准备好了！
The horses are in the stalls and ready to go.
看哪匹马最快跑出来！
Which horse will take off first?
出闸最快的就是「追风神驹」
It's Wind Chaser.
这匹热门马愈放愈快
It runs faster and faster.
后面的都很难追得上
The rest can hardly catch up.
上！上！上！
Go! Go! Go!
快！快！快！
Faster! Faster! Faster!
又爆冷，没有人中，库房又满泻了
No one wins. The warehouse must be filled with money.
潮哥
Big Bro Chiu.
喂
Hey.
卓老板，知道谁是昆西吗？
Mr Cheuk, you know who Kun-xi is?
我就是昆西
It's Kun-xi speaking.
上来海陆丰找我，保证你不会失望
Look me up in Guangdong. I won't let you down.
真的不干？赚到笑啊
You're really quitting? It's a cushy job.
难道我不知道？
You're telling me!
你跟老大说
Talk to Big Bro yourself.
惨了，这次倾家荡产入货
I have invested all I got in the goods.
金哥、忠哥，其实那些官
You already know all those officials
你们都相熟了吧？
and connections well…
你说什么？
What did you say?
船家
Fisherman!
是，欢哥
Yes, Bro Foon.
拿姓卓的电话给我
Give me Cheuk's number.
欢哥
Bro Foon.
有话说啊？
You got something to say?
没有
No.
拿来！
Give me the number!
是
Sure.
操！本想可以一战成名，光宗耀祖
Fuck! Thought I would be famous overnight.
白来一趟
What a waste of time!
扬不扬名不是问题
Fame is not an issue.
来到这儿，一个钱也没得分就回去
I can't just go back empty-handed.
还在这儿啃面包
Not to mention having to chew this bread here.
潮哥
Big Bro Chiu,
我们来到香港也不容易
coming to Hong Kong has not been easy for us.
总不能，就这样回去吧？
We can't just go back like this.
潮哥，真要我们回去吗？
Big Bro Chiu, you really want us to leave?
你们要是真有什么大茶饭的话
If you guys have something big in mind,
也算我们两兄弟一份
count us in!
我们什么都可以做的
We can do anything.
我很能守秘密的
I can keep a secret.
你说是潮哥就是潮哥吧
If you say you're Big Bro Chiu, then so be it.
我知道的了，您放心
I understand. Don't worry.
规矩我懂，一定不会跟别人乱说话的
I know the rules. It's between you and me.
我们也是讲义气的嘛
We have moral principle.
分了它
Share it.
说真的，我们可以的
Seriously, we can make it work.
你们三大贼王合作⋯
The 3 Kings of Thieves join forces…
多管闲事
Mind your own business.
知道这么多干吗？
不是要洗肾吗？还抽烟？
Aren't you on dialysis? Still smoking?
都说你狗改不了吃屎
Old habits die hard.
不是还生气吧？
Are you still angry with me?
你们想打劫楼下的金行吗？
You're planning to rob the gold shop downstairs?
还以为你真的来探我
I thought you're paying me a visit.
原来贪我这里方便
You're here just for the location.
你听我说
Listen to me…
还有什么好说？
No more!
先听我讲完
Listen to me…
我当你是兄弟，你当我是凯子啊！
I treat you as my brother. You treat me as a fool!
我没当你是凯子
I never treat you as a fool.
算了，不用说了！
Forget it! Just shut up!
我现在有妻有女
I have a wife and a daughter now.
生活过得很好
My life is great.
你不要来搞我家人好吗？
Can you leave my family alone?
这次是老大不对
I'm in the wrong this time.
你也知道现在赚钱不易
You know it's hard to make a living.
大家好兄弟
We're sworn brothers.
这次是我欠你的
I owe you this time.
这几天的事就算是粉笔字，抹了它
Forget what happened these past few days.
不要对人说
Keep it to yourself.
老大明天一早就走
I'll leave early tomorrow morning.
总之你不会再见到我
You won't see me again.
可乐叔叔
Uncle Coke.
还未睡？
Not in bed yet?
海陆丰
Guangdong province
香港西环码头
Sai Wan Container Terminal, Hong Kong
卓老板
Mr Cheuk,
久仰大名
I've heard so much about you.
人呢？
Where's Yip?
来，带你看点好东西
Let me show you something.
这边
This way.
卓老板，一路上来辛苦了
Mr  Cheuk. How was your journey?
待会带你吃点好的洗尘
I'll treat you to something special.
我们这里的虾蛄、咸蟹很有特色
Shrimps and crabs are local specialties.
吃完找两个发花帮你洗头
After food we'll find two shampoo girls for you.
来，这边这边
This way, please.
黑星、手榴弹、AK
Type 54 pistols, grenades, AK weapons.
什么货我都有
I've got all you want.
叶国欢呢？
Where's Yip?
外面那辆货车，还有一吨炸药
The truck outside holds a ton of dynamite.
砰！
Bang!
炸什么都行！
You can blow up whatever you want.
叶国欢啊！
Where's Yip?
全都部队出身
They were all retired soldiers.
胆大包天，身经百战！
They're fearless veterans in battles!
我要叶国欢！
I want Yip!
零钱！
Coin!
拿来！
Give it to me!
老大，再考虑一下
Big Bro, let's think it through.
拿来！
Give it to me!
现在也不错
We're doing all right.
为何要走回头路？
Why go back to our old business?
你教我做事？
Are you lecturing me?
能赚钱啊！
We're making money!
以前那种活，不能混一世
We can't be robbers for the rest of our lives!
你去做吧！
You do it!
你跟船家都谈好吧！
You have struck a deal with the Fisherman!
老大，他只是想想罢了
Big Bro, he was just thinking out loud.
要走就走
Leave if you want!
我不阻人发达！
I won't stop you!
现在几点？不用睡啊？
Do you know what time it is? You don't sleep?
拜山再说！
Go fuck yourself!
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
下来！
Come down!
那家伙收山了
Yip has retired!
他以前跟我的！
He used to be my man!
跟我合作不更好？
Am I not a better partner?
你是谁啊？
Who the hell are you?
喂？
Hello?
喂，卓子强
Hello, Cheuk.
我是叶国欢
It's Yip Kwok-foon speaking.
不会吧？
Are you kidding me?
你说是就是呀？
Why should I believe you?
我叶国欢有麟有角！
I am who I am!
不信我们见个面吧！
If you don't believe me, let's meet up!
你先等等
Wait. Got another call.
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
等什么？喂？
Wait for what? Hello?
喂？
Hello?
喂
Hey!
喂！
你死定了！
You are dead!
上去！
Go up!
喂？
Hello?
说话啊！
Speak!
是不是卓子强？
Are you Cheuk?
谁？
Who's speaking?
季正雄
Kwai Ching-hung.
要我帮忙吗？
Need my help?
不会吧！
Are you kidding me?
你说是就是了？
Do you have any proof?
86年油麻地东盛表行是我做的
I robbed Tung Shing Watch in 1986.
88年，旺角金太子门口
I killed 3 plainclothes
三个便衣探员是我杀的
in 1988.
还有92年置地广场⋯
And Landmark in 1992…
92年置地广场是叶国欢干的吧！
Wasn't it Yip who robbed Landmark in 1992!
别人说你就信
Don't be so gullible.
94年珍宝表行、前年好运佳
Jumbo Watch in 1994 and Lucky Guy Jewellery two years ago.
也是我干的
I did them all.
你以为只有他有AK吗？
Do you think only Yip had an AK-47?
他老哥爱上镜，警察又笨
He loved to be on camera and the cops were dumb.
我只好顺水推舟⋯　　你等一会！别挂啊
- I just took advantage of the situation…    - Hold on! Don't hang up.
刚刚最后一句你说什么？
What did you just say?
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
耍我啊？
Are you playing me?
就是你，叶国欢！
It's you, Yip!
92年置地、94年珍宝、前年好运佳
Landmark in 1992, Jumbo in 1994, and Lucky Guy two years ago.
也是你干的？
Are you responsible for all?
不是！
No!
我要遮遮掩掩？
I never did my jobs clandestinely!
鬼鬼祟祟？见不了人啊？
Why should I hide myself?
人齐了
We're all here.
你现在在哪？
Where are you right now?
香港
Hong Kong!
好，回香港再联络
I'll call you when I'm back in Hong Kong.
喂？
Hello?
季正雄，你还在吗？
Kwai Ching-hung, you still there?
喂？
Hello?
喂
Yes.
你现在在哪？
Where are you?
香港
Hong Kong.
回香港再联络
Call you when I'm back in Hong Kong.
再聊
Let's talk later.
你妈的！我们三大贼王合作
Motherfucker! The 3 Kings
关你屁事啊？
of Thieves have nothing to do with you.
一场来到
Since you're here,
怎样也要留下些什么吧？
you can't bail without leaving something.
是
Yes.
这里最多一千几百万
There's less than $10M here.
卓老板的性命
Mr Cheuk's life
怎么也值一个「红白蓝」吧！
worth at least $100M!
放下枪！
Put your guns down!
部队？走！
Retired soldiers? Go!
车匙
Car key.
车匙！
Car key!
当我说的是废话？
You think I'm bullshitting?
不当我是老大，散伙！
If you don't treat me as your Big Bro, let's split!
老大，一向都是你说了算
Big Bro, we always follow your orders.
你说放下枪便放下枪
You said “drop the guns,” we dropped the guns.
不做生意就不做生意
很难为呀？
Is that very hard for you?
不是⋯
No, we always follow you, Big Bro.
老大，你说什么就是什么
我们怎样也会挺你！
We support you no matter what!
看不起我？
Are you looking down on me?
沦落到要人挺？
I stoop so low that I need your support?
我没有谁也行！
I don't need you!
你们只是跟我的！
You're just my followers!
你们几个
Hey you!
这么晚在吵什么？
What are you fighting for?
不好意思，警察大哥，我们来旅游的
Sorry, we're tourists.
迷了路，便吵了两句
We got lost, so we quarreled.
现在楼上投诉
The residents upstairs filed a complaint.
证件呢？　　有
- Where are your IDs?    - Here.
我们打算坐船去澳门
We planned to take a boat to Macau
但不知这里是什么地方
but got lost here.
码头又不对
We couldn't find the pier.
心急之下，便吵了起来
So we quarreled.
报上电台
Call the station.
PC1844，叫电台
PC1844 calling the station. Send.
快点！追快点！
Quick!
不要让他逃掉！
Don't let him flee!
他妈的！
Motherfucker!
在前面！
He's in the front!
追他！
Go after him!
喂？狗叔，我找到他们
Hello? Uncle Dog, I've found them.
告诉你也不信，他俩给我打电话！
Believe it or not, they called me up!
还抢了一整吨炸药！
I even got a whole ton of dynamite!
这次行了，快找船上来接我
It will work this time. Get me a boat.
我想到干什么了！
I have an idea!
就把回归典礼给炸了！
We'll blow up the Handover ceremony!
到时无论要胁英女皇，还是中央政府
We can threaten either the British queen or the Chinese government.
我就不信这次不轰动！
It will create a stir for sure!
妈的！
What the fuck!
宵夜到了，回来没有？
The night snack is here. Back yet?
知道，马上回来
Coming back.
现在位置在投诉人大厦楼下
We're at the entrance to the complainant's building.
这里水静鹅飞，什么人也没有，完毕
It's quiet. No one's here. OVER.
文明些，不用高声说话
Be civilized. Don't talk too loud.
去澳门，是上环码头
If you go to Macau, take the ferry in Sheung Wan.
这里是西环
This is Sai Wan.
啊
Oh.
待会出去大街，坐的士
Go to the main street and take a cab.
「打的」啊！
Take a cab!
「大陆喱」，懵头懵脑
Mainlanders are numskulls.
快
Quick!
「大陆喱」？
Mainlanders?
我是叶国欢！
I'm Yip Kwok-foon!
武警
Military Police
服务员
Waiter.
你好，先生请问几位？
Sir, have you reserved a table?
姓陈的，订了房
I booked a room under the name of Chen.
订了房，好，稍等一下
Give me a second.
陈先生！来，麻烦这边请
Mr Chen. Please follow me.
请跟我来
This way, please.
喂
Hey.
饭到了没？
Where is our rice?
饭，稍等我一下
Rice? Give me a second.
饭马上来，很快
Your rice is coming right away.
不好意思，让你们久等
Sorry to keep you waiting.
谢谢
Thank you.
请慢用
Enjoy your food.
陈先生，这边请
Mr Chen. This way, please.
喂！你刚不是去厕所吗？
Hey! Haven't you gone to the bathroom just now?
等等，不要吐，吐在这里
Wait! Don't puke!
来⋯没事吧？
Are you all right?
不是去了洗手间吗？怎么会在这里出现
I thought you went to the restroom. Why are you here?
不好意思，这边请
I'm sorry. This way, please.
今天真的比较忙一点
We are super busy today.
喂　　这边请
- Hey!    - This way, please.
饭是冷的！
The rice is cold!
稍等我一下
Give me a second.
不好意思，饭是冷的吗？　　我要茶！
- I'm sorry. The rice is cold?    - I want tea.
好，等我一下，我帮你换过
Give me a second. I'll give you another bowl.
快！　　小姐，你告诉我，我自己去找吧
- Quick!    - Tell me the room number. I'll look for it myself.
我要茶！　　我带你去，等我一下
- I want tea.    - Give me a second.
茶，我帮你拿
Sure I'll get you tea.
等一下，你们都等我一下，马上回来
Give me a second. I'll be right back.
我们不会忘记你们
We should not forget you.
我们会以最关切的目光
And we should watch with the closest interest
看着你们开展非凡的新时代
as you embark on this new era of your remarkable history.